nicholas cronquist

web developer & consultant

🔀 nick@ncronquist.com 🔇 ncronquist.com 📞 (206) 886-1432 👂 Seattle, WA 💅 nicholaibee in ncronquist 🗘 ncronquist

summary

Web developer and consultant with experience leading teams in full life cycle software development. Particularly interested in building communication and automation tools. Experience with Rails, Angular.js, Node.js, .NET, PostgreSQL and MS SQL Server.

> skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES JavaScript Ruby SQL VB.net	FRAMEWORKS Rails Node.js Express Angular.js Sails.js	DATABASE TOOLS PostgreSQL Microsoft SQL Server Active Record Sequelize Waterline	OTHER TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS Git jQuery oAuth Data warehousing
HTML	541(5.]5	waterinic	Data conversion
rss			

experience

General Assembly

Seattle, WA

Web Development Immersive Student

Mar 2015 to Current

- Spent 70+ hour weeks learning full stack web development
- Front-end web development with Angular.js, JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap
- Back-end web development using PostgreSQL and MVC frameworks like Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Ruby on Rails, and Active Record
- Worked with web APIs like Twitter, Google, Facebook, and Reddit

Fast Enterprises

Vientiane, Laos

Implementation Consultant, E-Services Team Lead

Mar 2013 to Nov 2014

- Oversaw the design and development of the Laos e-services taxpayer website
- Managed fluctuating project requirements and variable time schedules to help Laos meet WTO standards
- Designed and implemented processes for taxpayers to register vehicles and to securely upload attachments to client servers
- Integrated antivirus protection into the e-services environment
- Converted data from the client's legacy systems to Fast Enterprises' Gentax system

Fast Enterprises

Baton Rouge, LA

Implementation Consultant, Registration and Collections Team Lead Jan 2011 to Mar 2013

- · Programmed complex redesign to suspend the licenses of individuals with delinquent tax liabilities
- Developed and maintained several data warehouse entities
- Created discovery processes based on the warehouse data to find new or missed revenue sources
- Produced data cubes, reports, and ad hoc queries to help the government agencies retrieve useful information from their data

> education

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive 2015

University of North Dakota

Bachelor of Business Administration Information Systems 2010

> projects

{DevBox}.Tools

http://www.devbox.tools

{DevBox}.Tools is a community-driven database of great developer tools where tools can be upvoted, reviewed, or saved to a user's personal tool box.

{DevBox}.Tools was built on Ruby on Rails, Angular, PostgreSQL, Material, and Materialize. Check it out on GitHub

- https://github.com/goopscoop/dev_box.

Schedulacity

https://schedulacity.herokuapp.com/

Schedulacity is a cloud-based client management app that allows independent instructors to schedule sessions, track attendance, and handle communication with their students.

Schedulacity was built on Ruby on Rails using the Google API for oAuth and calendar events as well as the Twilio API for text messaging. Check it out on GitHub

- https://github.com/ncronquist/schedulacity.

Listerlyify

https://listerlyify.herokuapp.com/

Listerlyify is a Twitter app that makes creating and managing your Twitter lists easier. Twitter lists are a great way to organize the people and companies you follow into logical groups, but the Twitter website makes them difficult to use. The goal of Listerlyify is to make it as quick and simple as possible.

Listerlyify was built on Node.js using the Twitter API. Check it out on GitHub

- https://github.com/ncronquist/listerlyify.